Guide to the Arthur Bohnen papers, 1918-1977, 1962-1972 (bulk)
Bohnen, Arthur papers, 1918-1977, 1962-1972 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Arthur Bohnen papers, 1918-1977, 1962-1972 (bulk)
3195
Arthur Bohnen, 1901-1978.
9.2 cubic ft.
Reports, speeches, job files, articles, publications, and a transcript of an interview.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, speeches, job files, articles, and publications of Arthur Bohnen, concerning city and regional planning, housing, and urban renewal. Also, transcript of interview of Otar Aamodt, by Bohnen, 1977.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Member, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, Ely Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports, speeches, job files, articles, and publications of Arthur Bohnen, concerning city and regional planning, housing, and urban renewal. Also, transcript of interview of Otar Aamodt, by Bohnen, 1977.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bohnen, Arthur, 1901-1978.; Aamodt, Otar.; Lambda Alpha International. Ely Chapter.
Subjects:
Housing.; City planning.; Regional planning.; Urban renewal.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Reports (including feasability, rental market, and land demand studies)
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Volunteer work for the International Executive Service Corps
Box 3
Series III. Publications by Bohnen and relating to his work
Boxes 3-4, 8
Series IV. Subject files (speeches, clippings, notes)
Boxes 4-5
Series V. Job files
Boxes 5-7
Series VI. Lambda Alpha International
Boxes 7-8
Series VII. Blueprints
Boxes 9-10
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Reports (including feasability, rental market, and land demand studies), 1960s-1970s (Box 1-2)
- Series II. Volunteer work for the International Executive Service Corps, ca. 1967-1974
  - I.E.S.C. (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Bogota, Colombia (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - A Proposed Housing Development Organization, Thessaloniki, Greece (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Nicaragua (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Colombia (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - C.I.T. Work Papers (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Colombia (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Greece (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Greece - Katsaros (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Greece, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Greece (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- Series III. Publications by Bohnen and relating to his work (Box 3-4,8)
- Series IV. Subject files (speeches, clippings, notes)
  - Ira Bach - Industrialized Housing (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rheem (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Printed material (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Systems (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Building records (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Cliff-May data (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Erection details - Modular walls & ext. walls (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cliff-May - Correction Manual (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Materials furnished in basic package - Cliff-May Homes (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cliff-May house - Parts list (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cliff-May - Carport/garage parts list (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Homeowner's book (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Purchasing - YMCA (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Urban renewal - Municipal Investment Trust (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Housing organization - Accounting (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Road show seminar (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Peace Corps (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - The Builder as Hero (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - From the Ground Up (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Retirement promotion (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Explanation of acct. system (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Civil riots, etc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - What About Federal Housing? (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sen. Bill 2246 Maybank Amendment - AB comment (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Speeches - Management (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Speeches - Housing general (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Platform app. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Speech material (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Books/publicatons (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - West Virginia U. papers (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Am. cities (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Unplanned Obsolescence (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - No. Car. Sav. & Loan speech (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Speeches (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - A Concept of a Home Building Organization ... (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Water Conditioner speech (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Some Comments on Housing for Chicago (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Module Your Own Plan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Advanced Housing (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Woman's City Club - Housing Institute (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - KEM-Weber (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lottery (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - T.U. ideas (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Industrial buildings (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Industrialized building (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Art Bohnen - Miscellaneous writings - Notes CBS (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - AB notes - CBS (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - AB paper - Centennial of Engineering (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - AB paper - Function of Acct. in Housing (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Tax-exempt housing (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - International cooperation - CBS (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - AB - Writings (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Misc. AB writings (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - General Motors of Housing (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Another Chicago Building First (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Chicago housing (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - American Standards Association (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Industrialized Building - Talk, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 23A)
  - Component Building Systems (CBS)
    - CBS (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - CBS technical items (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - CBS photos (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - CBS (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
    - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - SAGEAI-TEC (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - About CBS (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Chicago - Development (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - CIP (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - CBS notes (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - CBS - Promotional memos (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - House & Home article - boxes (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Lake Grove Village management (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Brockport (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Lake Grove (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Kroll (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - CBS resumé (Box 5, Folder 41-42)
    - Component Building Systems Ltd. by Arthur Bohnen (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - History of Prefabrication (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Building Research Station (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Series V. Job files
  - 9276 - Coops (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 5275 - Kansas City Continental Hotel (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Louisville (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Kraft Cheese (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - 8455 - Cent. Nat. Bank (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Melrose Park (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Scholz (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Castelwood Terrace (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Medinah (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 4325 - American Library Association (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 782H, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sanitary District RERC #214X (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Redevelopment areas, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Curr. Real Estate (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 640R - MWA Building (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Misc. RERC (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Decatur (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shagbark (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Elizabeth NJ (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 3240 N. Lake Shore Drive (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1112 Plans & sketches (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - 1112 brochure (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Johnson Wurm (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Washington National RERC #1801 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 307 Michigan Blvd. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - RERC Reports, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - HUD - Disaster proposal (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - CDA (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Coral Ridge (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Meade - Dayton, Ohio (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Colorado Springs (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 9385 - Cleveland (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Urban renewal - Shopping center study - Ira Bach, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Kankakee Eldorado Terrace (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Marion, Indiana (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Rockford (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - Rockford - Abegg (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Kurkjian (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - U of C - 52nd & Dorchester (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 57th & Dorchester (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Wayne - Bernard - U of C (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 537/39 Sheridan Rd. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Four Seasons - Fort Lauderdale (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - RLN jobs (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Richard Lawrence Nelson (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Nelson Kauman - Wheaton (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Melaniphy - Cook Co. Sheriff bid (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Melaniphy - Schaumburg (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Melaniphy - Pittsburgh (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Dwelling Assoc. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - McHenry - Ira Bach (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Round Lake (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bach - New towns (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nordic Hills air rights (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Summary acc., Nov. 25, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Series VI. Lambda Alpha International files
  - Minneapolis (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - LA Archives (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - LA correspondence - General (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - LA historian (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oliver Jones (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - LA - 1975 Congress (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Keystone Letter (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Rebedeau (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Hugo-Brunt (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bob Filley (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Keir Brooks (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - LA - Finch - Cornell (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - LA history (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - LA Board of Governors Meeting, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - LA Congress, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - LA Congress, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 26A)
  - Membership - Washington (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - LA Ritual (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - LA Board of Governors (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - LA Congress, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - LA past officers (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Memphis - Mid-American Chapter (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - NY membership (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Chapter historians (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - LA membership list (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - LA Philadelphia membership (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Simcoe membership (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - LA Foundation (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Clippings on LA members (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - LA Ely Chapter (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Thomas Klutznik (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Misc. Lambda Alpha documents (Box 7-8)
- Series VII. Blueprints (Box 9-10)